[
    {
        "question": "What does the Content-Type HTTP response header do?",
        "options": [
            "Not assigned",
            "It contains information about the software used by the origin server",
            "It specifies response MIME media types which are acceptable",
            "It indicates whether the response has been compressed or not",
            "It specifies the MIME media type of the associated resource"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 4,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the main technologies of Web 1.0?",
        "options": [
            "HTTP, RDF, MIME, URL",
            "HTTP, HTML, A JAX, URL",
            "HTTP, SPARQL, MIME, URL",
            "HTTP, HTML, MIME, URL",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an RDF triple?",
        "options": [
            "It is a relationship among rows belonging to three different tables",
            "It is a mechanism to encode information in a more secure way",
            "It is the way to connect HTTP, A JAX, and REST",
            "It is a statement of the form subject, predicate, object",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is an Element Node in XML?",
        "options": [
            "It represents the additional properties of a Node",
            "It is a fragment of unstructured information",
            "It is a logical grouping of the information represented by its descendant",
            "It is a fragment of textual content ignored in the processing",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "How does HTTP basic authentication work?",
        "options": [
            "Username and password are concatenated with a colon and then Base64 encoded in the WWW-Authenticate header",
            "Username and password are Base64 encoded and then concatenated with a colon in the WWW-Authenticate header",
            "Username and password are concatenated with a colon and then Base64 encoded in the Authorization header",
            "Username and password are Base64 encoded and then concatenated with a colon in the Authorization header",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a descriptive markup language?",
        "options": [
            "It defines the type or class of the content to indicate its intended use",
            "It provides the means for extending the vocabulary of the language",
            "Not assigned",
            "It refers to entities external to the document",
            "It contains commands to format and layout the content"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the application logic layer?",
        "options": [
            "To manage the persistent storage of the data",
            "To define and control the flow of operations in the application",
            "To manage the interaction with the user",
            "Not assigned",
            "To define the format and visualisation of information"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a single-tier architecture?",
        "options": [
            "A Web server/database server architecture",
            "A fat client/database server architecture",
            "Not assigned",
            "A thin client/Web server architecture",
            "A dumb terminal/mainframe architecture"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 4,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "How does the JSP technology work?",
        "options": [
            "Not assigned",
            "A pre-processor translates a JSP into a servlet and then the servlet processes the request",
            "The JSP page directly returns the response to the client, after processing the request",
            "The JSP is executed by an interpreter, like PHP, and processes the request",
            "The JSP page forwards the request to a servlet which processes it"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which elements are selected by the following CSS selector? <br>p a {<br>...<br>}",
        "options": [
            "Any &lt;a&gt; element inside a &lt;p&gt; element",
            "Any &lt;p&gt; element that has at least one &lt;a&gt; element as direct child",
            "Only &lt;a&gt; elements that are direct children of a &lt;p&gt; element",
            "Any &lt;p&gt; element which has an &lt;a&gt; element inside",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a jQuery object?",
        "options": [
            "It is an object similar to the DOM object in JavaScript.",
            "It is a set of zero or more DOM elements.",
            "Not assigned",
            "It is a single DOM element in jQuery language.",
            "It is an object similar to the Window object in JavaScript."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 1,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the dark Web?",
        "options": [
            "It is the Web ensuring anonymity",
            "It is the Web of static pages",
            "It is the not indexable Web",
            "It is the Web originated from databases",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the MIME multipart media type?",
        "options": [
            "To split a single body into multiple parts for more efficient transmission",
            "To multiplex multiple requests and responses into a single stream of data",
            "To describe content where one or more sets of data are combined into a single body",
            "To describe each single part constituting an URI",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you attach an external CSS to your HTML document?",
        "options": [
            "Insert the following element in the &lt;heading&gt; element &lt;link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" src=\"mystyle.css\"&gt;",
            "Insert the following element at the beginning of the &lt;body&gt; element &lt;link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" href=\"mystyle.css\"&gt;",
            "Insert the following element in the &lt;head&gt; element &lt;link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" href=\"mystyle.css\"&gt;",
            "Insert the following element in the &lt;head&gt; element &lt;link rel=\"stylesheet\" type=\"text/css\" src=\"mystyle.css\"&gt;",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the percent encoding?",
        "options": [
            "A compression encoding for textual resources",
            "The UTF-8 encoding of characters",
            "Not assigned",
            "An escaping of reserved and not plain ASCII characters in URI, based on % plus hexadecimal representation of octets",
            "A way to represent binary data in textual HTTP requests"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the issues of extended ASCII?",
        "options": [
            "Compatibility issues among different countries",
            "Waste of space issues due to many unused characters",
            "Not assigned",
            "Compatibility issues with the previous 7 bits version of ASCII",
            "Compatibility issues with the previous 32 bits version of Unicode"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is Maven?",
        "options": [
            "It is a site and documentation tool",
            "Not assigned",
            "It is a tool for managing the build process of Java software projects",
            "It is a Web server for running Java servlets",
            "It is a tool for managing the cooperative development of source code"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the following element represent? &lt;a src=&quot;http://www.example.com/index.html#bottom&quot;&gt;",
        "options": [
            "None of the other answers",
            "A link to a specific page fragment",
            "Not assigned",
            "A link to an element on the same page",
            "A link to a specific web page"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 0,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the <u>service</u> method in a Java servlet?",
        "options": [
            "Not assigned",
            "It allows the servlet to cleanup resources",
            "It allows the servlet to send a request",
            "It allows the servlet to respond to a request",
            "It allows the servlet to accept a response"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "How can you associate an image with its caption with HTML5?",
        "options": [
            "Use the &lt;figure&gt;, &lt;img&gt; and &lt;p&gt; elements",
            "Not assigned",
            "Use the &lt;figure&gt;, &lt;img&gt; and &lt;figcaption&gt; elements",
            "You need only the &lt;img&gt; and &lt;figcaption&gt; elements",
            "You need only the &lt;figure&gt; and &lt;figcaption&gt; elements"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is AJAX?",
        "options": [
            "It is a server-side technology to programmatically issue HTTP requests",
            "It is a technology to define the structure of a Web page",
            "It is a client-side technology to programmatically issue HTTP requests",
            "It is a technology to define the presentation of a Web page",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Who did invent the memex?",
        "options": [
            "Ted Nelson",
            "Douglas Engelbart",
            "Tim Berners-Lee",
            "Vannevar Bush",
            "Not assigned"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 3,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the HTTP PUT method do?",
        "options": [
            "It request the server to accept the entity enclosed in the request under the resource identified by a URI",
            "Not assigned",
            "It retrieves the resource identified by a URI",
            "Represents a request for information about the resource identified by a URI",
            "It requests that the resource identified by a URI is updated by the enclosed entity"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 4,
        "verified": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a browser?",
        "options": [
            "A client for sending email to an email server",
            "A server which provides Web pages",
            "A software which allows for displaying Web pages",
            "Not assigned",
            "Part of the HTTP protocol"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": 2,
        "verified": 1
    }
]
